<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Maif Muhammad Kriti</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Maif Muhammad Kriti</description><image><url>“https://i.postimg.cc/W4CNWHzy/van.jpg”</url><link>“https://i.postimg.cc/W4CNWHzy/van.jpg”</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:02:30 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://krititex.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why You Should Own A Feature Phone</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/posts/feat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:02:30 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://krititex.github.io/posts/feat/</guid><description>With the advent of smartphones, the decline of the once cherished feature phones was inevitable. Still, companies are manufacturing new feature phones, and people are going back to them for their convenience and minimalistic approach. I have seen many of my friends using one as a secondary phone besides their smartphone, and I also have one. Then again, why should you rethink these feature phones?
Because they are cheap. Well, it is not the sole reason, but for many, including myself, it might be the main selling point.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the advent of smartphones, the decline of the once cherished feature phones was inevitable. Still,
companies are manufacturing new feature phones, and people are going back to them for their convenience
and minimalistic approach. I have seen many of my friends using one as a secondary phone besides their
smartphone, and I also have one. Then again, why should you rethink these feature phones?</p>
<p>Because they are cheap. Well, it is not the sole reason, but for many, including myself, it might be the main
selling point. These are cheaper even than the most low-end smartphones. If cutting your cost is your priority,
why not give it a shot instead of buying a flagship phone once every year. A feature phone easily lasts for a
decent amount of years, as mine is in its fifth year now. It is surely worth the bucks.</p>
<p>Sick of buying tempered glasses and covers for your phone? Why not give these feature phones a try? These
phones are famous for their durability and are compact in every way. You might have had a good laugh at
those Nokia memes. There are a plethora of durability tests on the internet certifying their compactness, and
these phones hardly fall behind in that.</p>
<p>If making calls is your priority, these phones can serve you well. Every phone can do that, but feature phones
have always done that in the simplest way. In case of emergencies, they can come in handy.</p>
<p>The web of internet surrounds us zoomers all the time. So it is given that sometimes we become sick of it. A
much-needed respite from this can be utilized greatly if one is using a feature phone. First of all, it is hard
to use social media sites on your dumb phone, which can help you to curb your overall screen time. Other
reasons might be like you have this sudden urge to check what is trending on TikTok lately, but then you find
that there isn’t any app named TikTok out there. This saves you from unwanted cringe, keeping your mental
health in check.</p>
<p>Some of us are paranoid about our privacy. Isn’t the paranoia justified concerning how different sites often
track our movement on the internet? But it is not all grim news. Feature phones might be a suitable solution
to get rid of those telemetry apps that we are constantly using on our smartphones.</p>
<p>Well, Mr. Zucc, it was a pleasure having you around.</p>
<p>Also, these phones occupy less space in the pocket. While walking, smartphones can be a real bummer. As I
don’t want my smartphone to keep bugging me all the time, I just take my dumb phone instead while going
out.</p>
<p>And those of you, who are in college, in most cases, the authority won’t let you use any smartphones on the
campus. But they might allow these dumb phones. And if you’re using one, it could serve as a relief to your
worrying parents.</p>
<p>And there will be many more instances when you will be thanking your feature phone.</p>
<p>So why not turn around and be a feature phone hipster instead?</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Avalanche</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/posts/avalanche/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:52:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://krititex.github.io/posts/avalanche/</guid><description>Pouring the hot coffee in my mug, I settled myself into the chair outside my cottage. From there I could see the rocky mountains rising themselves as high as they could. The crispy wind drifted through the narrow valleys, carrying the sweet smell that genially spoke of spring. It was another lovely afternoon in the country sides. The steam rising from the mug blurred my vision as I gazed at the mountains.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pouring the hot coffee in my mug, I settled myself into the chair outside my
cottage. From there I could see the rocky mountains rising themselves as
high as they could. The crispy wind drifted through the narrow valleys, carrying
the sweet smell that genially spoke of spring. It was another lovely afternoon in
the country sides. The steam rising from the mug blurred my vision as I gazed
at the mountains. In no time, I found myself in the chasms of my past, surfing
through the evens and the odds.</p>
<p>It was pretty early in my climbing career. Being as passionate as one could
be, I craved to grab every opportunity out there. Given my enthusiasm, I did
not hesitate when I learned about that particular summit. Being a remote peak
in the Himalayas, it had gained little popularity back then. But there was
something in there that made me want to climb.</p>
<p>I took off from the base camp rather early. The air was quite cold, and
the glacial ambiance was always there. Besides, it was harder to climb in that
season. But as I was impatient, I wanted to climb as soon as possible.
The path kept becoming steep as time went by. Frost crept around me,
invading my senses altogether, leaving my soul more determined than ever. I
wanted to pour my strength, my hope, and my teachings all into it.</p>
<p>It took me seven entire days to reach the summit. The sun was already
down. A piece of moon hung low in the sky, casting its ethereal glow, framing
an idyllic, enchanted scene. Everything seemed infinitesimal up from there, even
the large village a few kilometers away felt tiny against the sky.</p>
<p>We, humans, were puny creatures. Despite that, at the peak of the mountain,
I felt like a behemoth. The sky still looked far away, away from my reach. But
I felt like I could still touch the sky, just for that moment. I can’t describe the
feelings in mere words. That’s what it was.</p>
<p>I wished to stay there for a long time, but the weather had bad news for
me. And I knew better. I started descending. I knew the risks of climbing,
and despite knowing all these, I had chosen this job. I would be the one to
blame if something bad happened. I had heard stories about climbers dying;
becoming amputated all the time. We who climbed all knew this. Accidents
weren’t aberrant. But what I expected the least happened. It was an avalanche.</p>
<p>I hadn’t reached halfway in my descent then. I started having difficulty in breathing, my body went chill from the clammy wind. It was strange, consid-
ering how I felt at the top. I saw ice starting to roll down at a sturdy pace, like those high waves in the sea. Watching it rushing towards me seized me numb.
They fumed my vision, and I no longer could maintain my stance. I became
disoriented.</p>
<p>My cords got dismantled, and the next thing I knew, I was falling along with
the snow. A gelid numbness permeated into my fleshes as I hit something as
solid as rock. I remember nothing after that. It’s like that moment in my life
never occurred once.</p>
<p>They claimed to find me submerged in the snow; unconscious. They told me
as if it was a miracle that I could even return with my bare life, having some
severe bone fractures. It took several months to rehabilitate.
But that incident deeply changed me on the inside. After that, I left my
house, from the grips of my abusive brother. Surviving an avalanche, did a great
job of breaking the plateau that had solidified over the years, cause that itself
needed a lot of courage.</p>
<p>As I was subjected to abuse, I always lacked self-confidence. Seeing people triumphing over the mountains, exploring the unknowns, I always found climbing to be courageous. That’s why I chose to be one.</p>
<p>After that expedition and returning from the verge of death, I finally understood that even if I had submitted myself to the longtime abuse, there was still time to act, to get myself out of that house. And that’s what I did. Since
then, I had conquered tons of mountains, saw the unseen, and finally retired as
an instructor in a climbing agency.</p>
<p>It had started raining by the time I finished my coffee. I came back to my
cottage hastily and began to prepare to make myself a lovely dinner. It was
long since I had settled myself among these lone mountains. I breathed the
mountain breeze, heard the hush of the wind prevailing in the distant valleys,
and ate what God had provided me with. Then I was grateful for still making
it through.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fallacies Concerning Creativity</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/posts/first/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:04:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://krititex.github.io/posts/first/</guid><description>Imagine yourself at an art gallery. You are looking through the beautiful paintings; done by incredible artists. Looking at those paintings, you are wondering “Wow! I wish I could be as creative as they are!” Then a sigh follows, reflecting your despair.
A majority of people think of creativity as a divine power a selected few inherently occupies. They can create whatever they want with their God-given talents. They can paint a beautiful picture, build a unique company having a unique concept behind it.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine yourself at an art gallery. You are looking through the beautiful paintings; done by incredible artists. Looking at those paintings, you are wondering “Wow! I wish I could be as creative as they are!” Then a sigh follows, reflecting your despair.</p>
<p>A majority of people think of creativity as a divine power a selected few inherently occupies. They can create whatever they want with their God-given talents. They can paint a beautiful picture, build a unique company having a unique concept behind it. Such notions are common in general. And it is not true at all.</p>
<p>Creativity is a process; the process of making something new by connecting existing thoughts. It is not something that comes out like a flash and boom! There you got something you have never seen before. It is not like that at all. Instead, you connect tiny bits of pieces and form a whole new thing. The creative process looks something like this. It is the culmination of experiences and practice.</p>
<p>By creating habits, you can hone your creativity. While we observe a mesmerizing artwork or excellent writing, we only see the outcome that is showed before us. However, we overlook what the person had to persevere to create those beautiful works. A good working schedule might be a great help for your creative process.</p>
<p>Haruki Murakami, whose works enrapture us, did not study ‘writing’ when he started. However, he used to read a lot from a very young age. He considers reading as the most prerequisite if you want to become a writer.</p>
<p>Discipline is a pivotal thing in the creative process. Haruki himself is a disciplined man. Every day, he wakes up early in the morning. He makes himself a cup of coffee and then sits down to write. He spends 4-5 hours on writing. In the afternoon he runs for ten kilometers or swims for fifteen hundred meters. While writing, he has to focus for a long time, and eventually, his mind gets jaded. Exercise appeases his mind and prepares him ready for the next day. At night, he goes to bed around nine p.m. This routine, he has been following it ever since. On an average day, he writes 800-1,200 words in the morning. With both physical and mental energy, he has been able to adhere to this schedule so far. And we got some phenomenal works of fiction.</p>
<p>By reading and experiencing different things, he accumulated the ingredients for his writing. And through writing regularly, he consolidates those pieces into a form of fiction. This cycle keeps him going.</p>
<p>Similar to Haruki Murakami; Stephen King, one of the most prolific writers in current time, writes about 2,000 words a day. And he makes sure not to miss a day.</p>
<p>Creativity is like building a muscle, you have to work through it every day. Psychology professor Barbara Kerr suggests, “approximately 22 percent of the variance [in creativity] is due to the influence of genes.” Some people are more creative than others, however, almost everyone is born with some creative skills. Therefore, assuming yourself as not creative is a pretty weak excuse to give.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>