<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>tech on Maif Muhammad Kriti</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in tech on Maif Muhammad Kriti</description><image><url>“https://i.postimg.cc/W4CNWHzy/van.jpg”</url><link>“https://i.postimg.cc/W4CNWHzy/van.jpg”</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:52:01 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://krititex.github.io/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avalanche</title><link>http://krititex.github.io/posts/avalanche/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 21:52:01 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://krititex.github.io/posts/avalanche/</guid><description>Pouring the hot coffee in my mug, I settled myself into the chair outside my cottage. From there I could see the rocky mountains rising themselves as high as they could. The crispy wind drifted through the narrow valleys, carrying the sweet smell that genially spoke of spring. It was another lovely afternoon in the country sides. The steam rising from the mug blurred my vision as I gazed at the mountains.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pouring the hot coffee in my mug, I settled myself into the chair outside my
cottage. From there I could see the rocky mountains rising themselves as
high as they could. The crispy wind drifted through the narrow valleys, carrying
the sweet smell that genially spoke of spring. It was another lovely afternoon in
the country sides. The steam rising from the mug blurred my vision as I gazed
at the mountains. In no time, I found myself in the chasms of my past, surfing
through the evens and the odds.</p>
<p>It was pretty early in my climbing career. Being as passionate as one could
be, I craved to grab every opportunity out there. Given my enthusiasm, I did
not hesitate when I learned about that particular summit. Being a remote peak
in the Himalayas, it had gained little popularity back then. But there was
something in there that made me want to climb.</p>
<p>I took off from the base camp rather early. The air was quite cold, and
the glacial ambiance was always there. Besides, it was harder to climb in that
season. But as I was impatient, I wanted to climb as soon as possible.
The path kept becoming steep as time went by. Frost crept around me,
invading my senses altogether, leaving my soul more determined than ever. I
wanted to pour my strength, my hope, and my teachings all into it.</p>
<p>It took me seven entire days to reach the summit. The sun was already
down. A piece of moon hung low in the sky, casting its ethereal glow, framing
an idyllic, enchanted scene. Everything seemed infinitesimal up from there, even
the large village a few kilometers away felt tiny against the sky.</p>
<p>We, humans, were puny creatures. Despite that, at the peak of the mountain,
I felt like a behemoth. The sky still looked far away, away from my reach. But
I felt like I could still touch the sky, just for that moment. I can’t describe the
feelings in mere words. That’s what it was.</p>
<p>I wished to stay there for a long time, but the weather had bad news for
me. And I knew better. I started descending. I knew the risks of climbing,
and despite knowing all these, I had chosen this job. I would be the one to
blame if something bad happened. I had heard stories about climbers dying;
becoming amputated all the time. We who climbed all knew this. Accidents
weren’t aberrant. But what I expected the least happened. It was an avalanche.</p>
<p>I hadn’t reached halfway in my descent then. I started having difficulty in breathing, my body went chill from the clammy wind. It was strange, consid-
ering how I felt at the top. I saw ice starting to roll down at a sturdy pace, like those high waves in the sea. Watching it rushing towards me seized me numb.
They fumed my vision, and I no longer could maintain my stance. I became
disoriented.</p>
<p>My cords got dismantled, and the next thing I knew, I was falling along with
the snow. A gelid numbness permeated into my fleshes as I hit something as
solid as rock. I remember nothing after that. It’s like that moment in my life
never occurred once.</p>
<p>They claimed to find me submerged in the snow; unconscious. They told me
as if it was a miracle that I could even return with my bare life, having some
severe bone fractures. It took several months to rehabilitate.
But that incident deeply changed me on the inside. After that, I left my
house, from the grips of my abusive brother. Surviving an avalanche, did a great
job of breaking the plateau that had solidified over the years, cause that itself
needed a lot of courage.</p>
<p>As I was subjected to abuse, I always lacked self-confidence. Seeing people triumphing over the mountains, exploring the unknowns, I always found climbing to be courageous. That’s why I chose to be one.</p>
<p>After that expedition and returning from the verge of death, I finally understood that even if I had submitted myself to the longtime abuse, there was still time to act, to get myself out of that house. And that’s what I did. Since
then, I had conquered tons of mountains, saw the unseen, and finally retired as
an instructor in a climbing agency.</p>
<p>It had started raining by the time I finished my coffee. I came back to my
cottage hastily and began to prepare to make myself a lovely dinner. It was
long since I had settled myself among these lone mountains. I breathed the
mountain breeze, heard the hush of the wind prevailing in the distant valleys,
and ate what God had provided me with. Then I was grateful for still making
it through.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>